Allen H. May

1732 Pershing Boulevard
Dayton, Ohio 45420
Home: 937-253-1574
email: allenhmay@gmail.com

Blog: http://allenmay.github.io/	Github: https://github.com/allenmay
Dribbble: https://dribbble.com/AllenHMay	LinkedIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/allenhmay
CodePen: http://codepen.io/AllenMay/	Twitter: https://twitter.com/AllenHMay
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/allen.may.98	

Developer / Designer / Project Lead

Successful 20 year career in the information technology field. Lead Contributor/Project Lead for web development, Internet integration, and software implementation projects. Ability to deliver solutions for internal operations, and external client needs. Demonstrated leadership by applying proven methods for success and sharing wisdom with the web development community.

Current volunteer positions: Co-Organizer for Web Developers, GemCityJS and Southwest Ohio Givecamp. **Career goal:** to be part of a small team of industry leaders bringing solutions for client needs. Contribute to projects that craft unique and engaging web experiences that are technically solid and fulfill the practical need.

Developer Tools Experience:

Bootstrap | CSS/CSS3 | Sass | HTML / HTML5 | Javascript / jQuery | WordPress / Drupal / Joomla | EmberJS | Git / Github | Grunt / Gulp | Jekyll | MVC Frameworks | Microsoft SQL / MySQL | Site Performance | PHP | Perl | Python | Django | Ruby on Rails | SVG | Command Line (variety of tools) | Test Driven Development | Workflows | Yaml | Yeoman | Responsive Design

Current Developer Focus	Historical Experience
 Jekyll - Blog maintenance on Github 	■ ASP.NET - C# /VB
■ Ember.js - Javscript Framework	■ PHP
 Web Application Frameworks 	 Intranet Systems
■ Ruby on Rails	 CRM (Customer Relationship Management)
■ Django	OnBase Workview / Case Management

Design Tools Experience:

Affinity Designer | Blender | Gimp | Google SketchUp | Hand Drawing | Illustrator | Inkscape | Photoshop

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CompuNet Clinical Laboratories – Dayton, Ohio

2008 - Current

Develope

Manage and maintain company websites, develop custom internal applications, automate legacy data migrations and project
manage company initiatives. Build custom business solutions using appropriate language, framework or systems. Technical
project manager and application developer for the company OnBase ECM. Database administrator over MySQL and
Microsoft SQL Server projects. Manage and develop reporting and business intelligence solutions for company and clients.
Provide creative solutions to automate processes and deliver business data.

Billback Systems - Dayton, Ohio

2005-2008

Implementation Specialist

Primary technical contact for clients during project implementation of the Billback proprietary software. Install and
customize software remotely and at client location. Project manage client expectations while working with their technical
and finance departments to identify customization and features needed. Install foundation system of Apache/Java/MS-SQL,
Billback application, edit XML and Java configuration files, troubleshooting system problems, hardware installation.
Provided maintenance of corporate website and develop internal PHP Intranet tools.

1732 Pershing Boulevard Dayton, Ohio 45420

Home: 937-253-1574 email: allenhmay@gmail.com

Dayton Digital Networks - Dayton, Ohio

2003-2005 (Full-time)

Owner/Operator and Chief Technology Manager

2005-2007 (Part-time)

 Oversee all business and technical needs including equipment/hardware upgrades, operating system upgrades, configuration, and account provisioning. Managed client needs, negotiated contract agreements, managed marketing campaigns while continuing to engage local businesses for sales opportunities.

MCSi, Dayton, Ohio 2000-2003

Web Administrator

Responsible for both the public-facing corporate website and the extensive internal employee-only website. Used
Dreamweaver, text editors and the command line to write and manage custom HTML, CSS, PHP, Perl and XML code.
Administrator of Linux web server: Care and maintenance, troubleshooting, content management, and automate deployment
processes.

LexisNexis, Dayton, Ohio 1995-2000

Software Engineering

• Processed LexisNexis proprietary data and formatted according to conversion projects' specifications. System engineering projects include: automated testing systems, 'The Spectrum Tool', and smaller systems within Spectrum. Also involved in troubleshooting UNIX, Mainframe, and Windows Operating Systems.

EDUCATION/TRAINING

- WorkView Implementation Hyland OnBase, May 2015
- Rails for Zombies 2 Code School, May 2015
- Rails for Zombies Redux Code School, April 2015
- try-sql Code School March, 2015

- Warming Up With Ember.js Code School, March 2015
- Writing Queries Using Microsoft SQL Server 2008
 Transact-SQL Microsoft, May 2011
- What's New in Microsoft SQL Server 2008 for Database Development Microsoft, April 2010

A.A.S Electronics Engineering Technology, RETS Technical Center, 1991 C Programming using Turbo C++/UNIX Operating System – Sinclair Community College

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Co-Organizer - Dayton Web Developers http://www.meetup.com/dayton-web-developers/ January 2015 - Current	Co-Organizer - Southwest Ohio Givecamp http://southwestohiogivecamp.org/ March 2015 - Current
I help plan and host monthly meetings, recruit content specialists to speak at meetings and solicit sponsorship for the group.	I help manage the http://southwestohiogivecamp.org/ website content and provide gather trending data through analytics.
Co-Organizer - GemCityJS http://GemCityJS.com January 2015 - Current	
I help plan and host monthly meetings, recruit content specialists to speak at meetings and solicit sponsorship for the group.	